KHALEL CORONA

DATA SCIENTIST





805-744-5022



coronakhalel@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/khalel-corona



youtube.com/@khalelcorona

SKILLS

- Expert-level skills in Stata, statistical software package for data manipulation, visualization, statistics, and automated reporting
- Extremely experienced with data processing, the method of collecting raw data and translating it into usable information
- Proficient in data visualizations, the representation of data through use of common graphics, such as charts, plots, infographics, and even animations
- Advanced in Python (packages: Numpy, Pandas, and Matplotlib) for the purpose of data science, which leverages math, statistics, and specialized programming to uncover actionable insights hidden in an organization's data
- Advanced in Machine Learning (packages: Scikit, Tensorflow, Keras), a branch of artificial intelligence and computer science which focuses on the use of data and algorithms to imitate the way that humans learn, gradually improving its accuracy

EDUCATION

ECONOMICS B.S.

Brigham Young University

April 2021 - April 2023

VOLUNTEER WORK

MULTILINGUAL TEACHER

Religious Organization

November 2018 - November 2020

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

After receiving an associates degree on the Dean's List by the age of 17, I volunteered for 2 years in another country, speaking multiple languages (English, Spanish, and French) as a teacher to refugees from around the world. Thereafter, I received my bachelor's degree in BYU's Economics department in only 2 years, with a cumulative GPA above 3.9, receiving full-tuition scholarships for academic excellence. I have both taken PhD equivalent courses in advanced econometric theory and conducted multiple research projects pulling from big data and a variety of data science softwares for the purpose of data processing, data visualization, statistical data analysis, and machine learning. I take honor in attempting to be humble enough to be constantly learning and diligent enough to excel at any responsibility that is entrusted to me. This is what makes me unique.

EXPERIENCE

ECONOMETRICIAN

Brigham Young University

April 2021 - April 2023

- Use advanced mathematics to produce sample estimates of population statistics and quantitative relationships in research, for example, in one research project, I discovered that US states who implemented <u>covid mask</u> <u>mandates</u> truly experienced a decay in the growth of new covid cases in comparison to states who did not implement mask mandates
- Master using data science softwares such as Stata and Python for the purpose
 of causal inference, hypothesis testing, and machine learning, for example, in
 another research project, I discovered that the true death toll of covid was
 actually 28% above the CDC's official report of 350,000 deaths in the US for
 2020

ECONOMICS RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Brigham Young University

May 2022 - August 2022

- Assist the BYU Economics research team in refining a machine learning program designed to automate genealogical work, enabling African-Americans to have pedigrees that are now more connected than even white Americans, something that has not been accomplished until this project
- Assist a Stanford University project in collecting and managing data for graduate-level research aimed to quantify the relationship between social mobility and education, a topic of much concern in today's political arena; this research still continues up to this day

ECONOMICS TEACHING ASSISTANT

Brigham Young University

August 2022 - January 2023

- Assist a class of 500 students in comprehending fundamental economic principles and theories in the real world
- Grade the quality of work produced by students in analyzing and expounding upon economic phenomena